<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>server on </title>
    <link>https://johannes-pirmann.com/categories/server/</link>
    <description>Recent content in server on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 18:39:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://johannes-pirmann.com/categories/server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setup Ubuntu 20.04 Server with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://johannes-pirmann.com/post/setup-ubuntu-20-04-server-with-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 18:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johannes-pirmann.com/post/setup-ubuntu-20-04-server-with-ansible/</guid>
      
        <description>If you want a more hands on approach you can follow the following tutorial: https://johannes-pirmann.com/setup-ubuntu-20-04/
Prerequisites  An Ubuntu 20.04 Server with the LAMP-Stack installed. A root user and password A domain The Ansible Playbook: https://github.com/Pirmann-Media/ansible-playbooks/tree/main/ubuntu-20-04-setup  Step 1 - Get the Playbook Go to the GitHub Repository and download the ansible playbook.
Step 2 - Adapt the provision.yml file Go to the provision.yml file and set your desired username and the corresponding password.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Ubuntu 20.04</title>
      <link>https://johannes-pirmann.com/post/setup-ubuntu-20-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 16:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johannes-pirmann.com/post/setup-ubuntu-20-04/</guid>
      
        <description>Introduction In this tutorial you will learn how to setup an Ubuntu server. This includes how to create a non-root user, enable SSH login, disable root login and enable a rudimentary firewall.
 This article was first published at Hetzner Community: https://community.hetzner.com/tutorials/setup-ubuntu-20-04
 Step 1 - Login to your new serverLogin as the root user to your new Ubuntu 20.04 server: ssh root@10.0.0.1  If you already set up your server with an SSH key and it isn&amp;rsquo;t your default key you need to tell your machine where to find it:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to backup and restore Ghost</title>
      <link>https://johannes-pirmann.com/post/backup-and-restore-ghost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 14:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johannes-pirmann.com/post/backup-and-restore-ghost/</guid>
      
        <description>In this article I will describe how to create a backup of the Ghost database and directory, back it up and restore it.
Prerequisites:  Ghost running on a VPS Google Drive, or similar  Creating the Backup Step 1 - Backup the database In this step we will create a copy of the database and the directory.
Step 1.1 - Create a mysql backup user Within your server login to mysql:</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>